Rishi Bagga

Technical AEM Solutions Consultant at Adobe



LONDON, UK | MOBILE: 07947350277 | EMAIL ADDRESS: RISHI_345@HOTMAIL.CO.UK

Profile Statement

My work style is simplicity above all, and I take a lot of inspiration from the quote "If you can't explain it simply, you don't understand it well enough".

As an accomplished Solution Consultant, with a background in Adobe Marketing Products and over 4 years' experience in the industry, I have provided solutions and consulting services for clients across a wide range of sectors including Public Sector (Banking and Education), Manufacturing, Retail, Travel and Transport, Health, Finance, and Energy.

I am comfortable engaging at board level, shaping solutions and strategy, as well as leading project delivery to take a solution through implementation and deployment. As an accomplished Solutions Consultant, I support the Account Executives through the sales process, and supported customers through the proof of concept and transition to the account support team. In my role, I am responsible for technical account management, product demonstration, solution value propositions, custom business case creation and possess a high-level of professionalism as the technical point of contact with the customer. As part of this, my role was to create custom demos, develop and presents reporting to address each business requirement, and addresses all technical requests during the sales process.

Experience

February, 2020 - Present

Solutions Consultant Adobe Systems

Undertook many roles across pre-sales, consulting, and delivery. Delivery roles ranged from solo consulting engagements lasting a few weeks, through to large scale implementation projects lasting over a year.

- Involved in opportunities from the qualification phase right through to closure and transition to the implementation team- supporting the client training during hand-over.
- Showcasing competency in AEM solution end-to-end from solution, positioning, demo, sizing, architecture.
- Wrote proposals, responded to major RFPs, POC demos, competitor analysis and effective demonstration of the Adobe Marketing Cloud solutions.
- Work hands on with R&D and Marketing to define and drive the continued improvement and future development of our products.
- Running workshops for colleagues, educating on new releases and capabilities of products. Pitches to CXO-level executives and presenting to large audiences.
- Support the sales team in closing Experience Cloud opportunities, with core focus on AS, AA, AT and AEM.

July, 2017 - July 28th 2018

Business Analyst 20th Century Fox

- Provide day to day support across all Fox applications within scope to understand clients' requirements.
- Supporting clients with integrating and implementing new technologies.
- Participate in meetings with the business as required to increase knowledge of business processes, resolve issues and improve the way IT works with the business.

Education

2015 – 2019 1:1 City, University of London Computer Science BSc

2012 -2014 **Greenford Sixth form** A Levels: AA - Business, B - English, C- ICT. AS Level: C - Politics

2007–2012 **Dormers Wells High School** 10 GCSEs grades A-C's including English, Math's and Science.

Key Projects

Movie search mobile application - Android Studio.

Tutoring Website - bridging the gap between Tutors and Students where students could find tutors that match their requirements, vice versa. HTML/ JavaScript

Developed a Translation Application -

Android helping users to communicate with people from around the world through speech, text and the camera. I successfully deployed this on the Google Play store in the beginning of 2020.

Projects & Achievements

- Certifications: Cache OO Systems 2018. Adobe Experience Manager, Analytics, Target, Sign 2020
- Completed a two-player game in Java;
 Processing. Completed June 2016.
- Successfully led delivery projects with values up to £1.5M and team sizes up to 10. AEM Certified.
- Led a group of 30 students through a Python 101 crash course.

Experience

October 2016 - December 2018

Sales Demonstrator Google

- Providing exceptional customer service to customers, depicting the uniqueness
 of Google and its products, i.e. the Google Pixel phone, building rapport and
 maintaining a professional image.
- Building & maintaining extensive knowledge about google products.

Aug 2013 - Aug 2013

Digital Marketing Arch Agilisys

- Working on a project for Godaddy.com to ensure that the correct marketing method attracted the customers attention leading them to purchase the domains and designs of their website.
- Team oriented managing a project that was given by a large-scale business. I
 worked in a team and independently presenting my ideas to the group, finding
 solutions to complex problems, highlighting the factors to reach our targets.

Additional Experience

June 2012 - Present Best

Private Tutor Tutoring At Its

Tutoring children aged 7-19 English, Math, Science and Coding in JavaScript, Python and HTML.

June 2015 - Oct 2015 Lettings Negotiator Stamford's Estate Agent

Ability to communicate verbally with people inside and outside of the organisation, meeting targets by selling and influencing others.

Sept 2014 – April 2015 Contact Centre Representative Metro Bank

Proficiency with computer software programs, making decisions and solving problems. Completing customer transactions quickly and efficiently, following the security procedures.

April 2014 – Nov 2014 Contact Centre Market Probe Europe

The ability to work in a team structure by making outbound calls to customers for market research purposes, collecting significant data, for **Skills and Interests** example feedback on previously taken out insurances.

Skills: Microsoft Office | AEM | JavaScript | Python | CRM

Interests: Career Consulting, Analytics, Teaching, Speaking at Schools, Gym

Languages: Hindi, Punjabi, Urdu.

Software Systems & Programming Skills

- Programming Languages Java, HTML5, CRM, Python, C++, Android Studio, MYSQL, T24, 4TRESS, SPSS
- Adobe Software; Adobe Analytics, Target, AEM, Sign, Photoshop, XD, Premier Rush.
- Analytical and problem-solving skills -Level-headed and resilient when identifying issues to overcome the problem and acting on an agreed action for me to deliver.
- Natural Communicator Ability to multi-task; strong sense of ownership and urgency; ability to improvise. Selfmotivated with a strong drive to succeed in a highly dynamic environment with variable priorities.
- Collaborative approach I motivate and encourage my team members to work harder to reach our target. My people skills bring me together with other users and technology to design and build creative experiences, maintaining positive relationships with clients and colleagues.
- Leadership & Initiative I thrive in positions of responsibility and have the intuition for leading a team and stepping up to a challenge.
- Commercial Awareness Ability to quickly understand the fundamentals of an industry and how it works. I ensure I have a good understanding of hot topics across a variety of industries.